# Vikash PR

+91-93444-87074 · mail@vikashpr.com · @<u>vikashpr.com</u> Namakkal, TN, India 636202

# STUDENT / DEVELOPER

A ambitious and driven Computer Science student at SRM University with 3 years of professional experience in software development majorly web development. I'm extremely interested in pursuing independent research and a good internship would consolidate my future career choice. I'm personally interested in the application of computer-science in the field of medicine, Education.

### **KEY COMPETENCIES**

Web development Strategic planning Python
Ability to maintain quality in work

Git / Github Team Collaboration

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# WEBILICIOUS IT Services and IT Consulting webilicious.in Software developer

April 2020 - Present

Being part of core web development team of 13 students with expertise in various domain like web development, App development, Block chain, cybersecurity, Marketing since 2020 after completing my high school at the age of 16.

#### Accomplishments:

- Built online platform e-commerce international logistics company Colombo mail with over 2500 users.
- Won 2nd position in Chennai hacks representing team Webilicious.

# TEAM ENVISION, AARUUSH at SRM IST FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Aug 2021 - Present

Been a committee member in my 3rd & 4th semester and promoted to committee head in 3rd year, now leading student team of 30 web developers and managing 300 volunteers of TeamEnvision.

## Accomplishments:

- Built TeamEnvision main website for Aaruush 2022 Edition
- Organised Teach Bot event (Teaching MERN stack for students)

# E-MOBILITY RESEARCH CENTRE (EMRC) at SMR IST RESEARCH INTERN

Aug 2022 - Present

Working on a efficient EV charging eco-system by considering various factors of EV cars and environmental situations including the availability of charging node and efficient charging method.

#### Accomplishments:

 Built online Simulation platform where the user can get recommendation for the most efficient charging node nearby and user can use the platform to get shortest road routing in the platform which is implemented with the help of Google Map API.

# PNEUMA IT Services and IT Consulting at NEW DELHI FRONT-END INTERN

Aug 2022 - Present

Working as a remote Front-End developer Intern using technologies like NextJs, ReactJs, Sass, Bootstrap.

#### Accomplishments:

Building & Maintaining Front-End for PNEUMA's aviation reservation software.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **HIGH SCHOOL & MIDDLE SCHOOL**

2014 - 2020

Senthil Public School, Salem / FIITJEE.

• CGPA: 79%

· Course: Computer Maths

· CBSE Board

#### **BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE**

2020 - Present

SRM Institute of Science & Technology, Chennai

CGPA: 9.51Course: CSE core

# **PROJECTS**

### Dr.Bot [Firebase, dialogflow, JS]

24 hours

Dr. Bot is a NLP based chatbot for remote patient disease diagnosing, integrated with Google assistant .

• Dr. Bot was awarded 2nd position in Chennai Hacks hackathon

### Colombomail.lk [ Vue.js, Sass, Vuetify, JS ]

2021 - Present | Regularly updating

Colombomail is a international logistic courier delivery services company

- Developed the Colombomail service website
- Worked in admin panel of Colombo mail which manages the couriers around the world
- · maintaining the website & admin panel

### Pneuma.club [ NextJs, Sass, Bootstrap ]

2022 - Present

Pneuma.club is an online flight reservation software. Project is built as a part of FRONT-END internship

Developing and maintaining Front-End for Pneuma.club

#### EV-Navigator [ Vuejs, Sass, GoogleMap API ]

2022 - Present

EV-navigator is a effective solution for navigating EV's by proritisiing charging nodes

This project is built as a part of Internship at E-MOBILITY RESEARCH CENTRE (EMRC)

### VikashPR.com [ HTML, CSS, JS, FIREBSE, Github Actions, CloudFlare ]

1 Month

VikashPR.com is personal portfolio website.

· This is a personal project to showcase achievements, awards, projects etc..

#### **VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES**

#### **Events:**

 Organised Engineers day event for two days under guidance of school of computing SRM IST and received certificate of appreciation from HOD C-Tech department.

## **Social Service:**

- Conducted Social service at "Good life children home" Chennai as a part of SRM IST outreach program
- Created an initiative "Gurukulam" to teach underprivileged and orphaned students and organised online class for the elementary school students. As a part of University activity.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Scaler Academy Hackthon:Won 2nd Position winning price of 30,000 INR2022State Level Yoga Competition:Won 1nd place 2 times for consecutive years2012, 2013District Level Yoga Competition:Won 1nd place 2 times for consecutive years2012, 2013